Finding Aid for the Carleton Watkins Collection of Photographs LSC.0599
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Missions
  - Mission, San Miguel San Luis Obispo County, California, Established July 25th, 1797., [ca. 1882]; Watkins Series no. 1229; Plate Dimensions: 38 × 54 Matt Dimensions: 50 × 65 Mammoth print No visible damage. All edges cockled. Fabric tape residue along LE. BRC: creased. TE: loss and surface loss 12" from RE. Small surface loss 2" from LE. (Box 7)
  - Mission, San Antonio de Padua. Monterey County, California, Established July 14th, 1771. Watkins' New Series, 26 New Montgomery Street, San Francisco., Watkins Series no. 1230; Plate Dimensions: 38 × 54 Matt Dimensions: 61 × 76 Mammoth print No visible damage. Fabric tape residue on LE. Corners not visible due to mounting. BE: tears 8-3/8" & 15-1/4" from LE. TE: surface loss 8-1/4" & 10-3/4" from LE. (Box 8)
  - Mission, San Antonio de Padua Monterey County, California, Established July 14th, 1771., [ca. 1882]; Watkins Series no. 1231; Plate Dimensions: 38 × 54 Matt Dimensions: 50 × 65 Mammoth print No visible damage. Fabic tape residue down LE. Tear on TE, 3 inches from TLC, tear is 1 inch straight down, 2 inches at 45 degree angle to right. Small chips along TE, left end of BE. BLC, TLC, TRC slightly worn. BRC moderately worn. All edges cockled. Small tear BE, 9-1/4" from LC. (Box 8)
  - Mission, San Carlos del Carmelo. Monterey County, California, Established June 3d, 1770. Watkins' New Series, 26 New Montgomery Street, San Francisco., Watkins Series no. 1232; Plate Dimensions: 38 × 54 Matt Dimensions: 61 × 76 Mammoth print No visible damage. Corners not visible due to mounting. Fabric tape residue LE. All edges cockled. Tears: 3- 3/4" & 19" from LE. RE loss 9" from BE. TE tear 7-3/8" from LE. (Box 8)
  - Mission, San Carlos del Carmelo Monterey County, California, Established June 3d, 1770. View looking west, with glimpse of Carmel Bay., [ca. 1882]; Watkins Series no. 1233; Plate Dimensions: 38 × 54 Matt Dimensions: 50 × 65 Mammoth print No visible damage. Fabric tape residue along LE. BE discolored. BE: 3/4" tear, 2" from left. BE: 1/2" loss, 4- 3/4" from LE. BE: small nick, 9-3/8" from LE. BE: 1/2" tear, 4-3/4" from RE. RE: small loss 1-1/2"from BE. RE: tiny loss 2-5/8" from BE. RE: small tear 5-1/8" from BE. RE: small loss 5-1/2" to 6" from BE. TRC & BRC loss, TEC small chips. (Box 8)
  - [Mission San Luis Rey de Francia, June 13th 1798.] Watkins' New Cabinet Series. Yosemite and Pacific Coast, 427 Montgomery St., San Francisco, Watkins Series no. 4615; Matt Dimensions: 16.5 × 10.5 Cabinet card (Box 1, Folder 1/5)
  - Mission, San Juan Bautista San Benito County, California, Established June 24th, 1797., [ca. 1882]; Watkins Series no. 1234; Plate Dimensions: 38 × 54 Matt Dimensions: 50 × 65 Mammoth print No visible damage. All edges cockled. Fabric tape residue along LE. BLC & BRC loss. BE discolored. BE: 1- 1/2" tear, 7-1/4" from LE. BE: small tear, 12-1/2" from LE. Brown spot near BRC. TE: small tear, 7-3/4" from LE. (Box 8)
  - Mission, Santa Clara Santa Clara County, California, Established Jan. 18th, 1777., [ca. 1882]; Watkins Series no. 1235; Plate Dimensions: 38 × 54 Matt Dimensions: 50 × 65 Mammoth print No visible damage. All edges cockled. Fabric tape residue along LE. BLC creased, BRC creased with loss. RE: small tear, 9-1/2" from BE. TRC loss. TE: crease, 3" from RE. TE: crease, 11-1/2" to 12-1/4" from RE. TE: 1/2" x 1/4" piece missing, 12-1/2" from RE. 1/4" line just below TE, 7-1/4" from RE. (Box 9)
  - Mission, San Francisco de Asis San Francisco County, California, Established Oct. 4th, 1776., [ca. 1882]; Watkins Series no. 1236; Plate Dimensions: 38 × 54 Matt Dimensions: 50 × 65 Mammoth print Black spot, 5-1/2" to left of top of flagpole. Black spot, 2-1/4" above top of flagpole. Black spot, 3" above and to right of flagpole. Black spot, 4-1/2" to right of flagpole. All edges cockled. Fabric tape residue along LE. BLC, BRC, TRC loss. BLC surface loss. BE: 6" from LE, 1-1/4" x 1/4" missing. BE: small tear, 10-3/4" from LE. Small tear, 12-3/4" from LE. BE: small tear, 15" from LE. BE: small tear, 8" from RE. BE: small tear, 6-7/8" from RE. RE: small tear, 2" from bottom. TE: surface loss, 14" from right edge. TE: small tear, 2" from LE. (Box 9)
  - Mission, San Jose Alemeda County, California, Established June 11th, 1797., [ca. 1882]; Watkins Series no. 1237; Plate Dimensions: 38 × 54 Matt Dimensions: 50 × 65 Mammoth print Small edge tear BE 4-5/8" from BRC. Creasing along BE. Paper label spotted and stained. Discolored overall, brittle at edges. Loss TRC. Black spots at RE. BC TC & CR edges cockled. Fabric tape residue along LE. 1" tear at edge BC. Scattered dark specks overall. (Box 9)
  - [Mission San Juan Capistrano, founded Nov. 1st 1776] Watkins' New Cabinet Series. Yosemite and Pacific Coast, 427 Montgomery St., San Francisco, Watkins Series no. 4618; Matt Dimensions: 16.5 × 10.5 Cabinet card (Box 1, Folder 1/5)
  - Mission San Juan Capistrano, Estab. Nov. 1st, 1776. From Watkins' Yosemite Art Gallery, Portrait and Landscape, 26 Montgomery Street, and Woodward's Gardens, S.F., Watkins Series no. 4623; Matt Dimensions: 16.5 × 10.5 Cabinet card (Box 1, Folder 1/5)
  - Mission San Juan Capistrano, Estab. Nov. 1st, 1776. From Watkins' Yosemite Art Gallery, Portrait and Landscape, 26 Montgomery Street, and Woodward's Gardens, S.F., Watkins Series no. 4624; Matt Dimensions: 16.5 × 10.5 Cabinet card (Box 1, Folder 1/5)
  - [Mission San Juan Capistrano, Nov. 1st 1776] Watkins' New Cabinet Series. Yosemite and Pacific Coast, 427 Montgomery St., San Francisco, Watkins Series no. 4626; Matt Dimensions: 16.5 × 10.5 Cabinet card (Box 1, Folder 1/5)
- Pacific Coast
  - Hotel Del Monte, Monterey - Rose Garden. Watkins' New Series Yosemite and Pacific Coast, 427 Montgomery St., San Francisco, Watkins Series no. 152; Matt Dimensions: 14 × 22 Boudoir card (Box 1, Folder 2/5)
  - Hotel Del Monte, Monterey - Lawn View. Watkins' New Series, Yosemite and Pacific Coast, 427 Montgomery St, San Francisco, Watkins Series no. 308; Matt Dimensions: 14 × 22 Boudoir card (Box 1, Folder 2/5)
  - Young Squid Catchers. Chinese Fishery, Monterey. Watkins' New Boudoir Series Yo Semite and Pacific Coast, 427 Montgomery Street, San Francisco, Watkins Series no. 327; Matt Dimensions: 14 × 22 Boudoir card (Box Missing)
  - "As the twig is bent, the Tree's Inclined," 18 Mile Drive, Monterey, Calif. Watkins' New Series, Yosemite and Pacific Coast, 427 Montgomery Street, S.F., Watkins Series no. B170; Matt Dimensions: 14 × 22 Boudoir card (Box 1, Folder 2/5)
  - Hotel Del Monte, Monterey. Lawn View. Watkins' New Boudoir Series Yo Semite and Pacific Coast, 427 Montgomery Street, San Francisco., Watkins Series no. B307; Matt Dimensions: 14 × 22 Boudoir card (Box 1, Folder 2/5)
  - Hotel Del Monte, Monterey. Fern Bank. Watkins' New Boudoir Series Yo Semite and Pacific Coast, 427 Montgomery Street, San Francisco, Watkins Series no. B315; Matt Dimensions: 14 × 22 Boudoir card (Box 1, Folder 2/5)
  - The Squid Fleet on shore, Chinese Fishery, Monterey. Watkins' New Boudoir Series Yo Semite and Pacific Coast, 427 Montgomery Street, San Francisco, Watkins Series no. B326; Matt Dimensions: 14 × 22 Boudoir card (Box 1, Folder 2/5)
  - Lawn View, Hotel Del Monte, Monterey, Cal. Watkins' New Series, Yosemite and Pacific Coast, 26 New Montgomery St., under Palace Hotel, S.F., Watkins Series no. B3832; Matt Dimensions: 14 × 22 Boudoir card (Box 1, Folder 2/5)
  - Bridge, near Pescadero, 18 Mile Drive, Monterey. Watkins' New Boudoir Series Yo Semite and Pacific Coast, 427 Montgomery Street, San Francisco, Watkins Series no. B3883; Matt Dimensions: 14 × 22 Boudoir card (Box 1, Folder 2/5)
  - Santa Monica Hotel. Watkins' New Boudoir Series Yo Semite and Pacific Coast, 427 Montgomery Street, San Francisco, Watkins Series no. B4751; Matt Dimensions: 14 × 22 Boudoir card (Box 1, Folder 2/5)
  - [Santa Monica Hotel], Watkins Series no. B4751; Plate Dimensions: 20.1 × 23 Copy (not original) (Box 1, Folder 2/5)
  - At Pacific Grove, Monterey. Watkins' New Boudoir Series Yo Semite and Pacific Coast, 427 Montgomery Street, San Francisco, ID no. SCW64; Matt Dimensions: 14 × 22 Boudoir card (Box 1, Folder 2/5)
- Various
  - [Salt Lake City, Union Pacific Railroad], [ca. 1873]; ID no. SCW65; Plate Dimensions: 14.3 × 18.1 (Box 1, Folder 4/5)
  - [Unidentified young man in uniform], ID no. SCW66; Matt Dimensions: 16.5 × 10.5 Cabinet card (Box 1, Folder 2/5)
  - [V.B. Gates], ID no. SCW67; Matt Dimensions: 10.5 × 6.5 Cabinet card (Box 1, Folder 2/5)
  - [Unidentified grove view], ID no. SCW68; Plate Dimensions: 38.5 × 53.5 Mammoth print Triangular loss from 7" to 9-1/8" from LE. Small loss 4" from RE. Small loss 2" from RE. Small loss 10-3/8" & 7" from TE. Small losses 14", 8-1/2", 1-7/8", 1-1/8" from LE. Tears 5-1/4" & 2" from BE. No support. (Box 9)
  - [Casa Grande, Pre-Historic Ruins Arizona] [close up], [1880]; ID no. SCW69; Plate Dimensions: 39 × 53.5 Matt Dimensions: 55.5 × 71 Mammoth print No visible damage. All edges cockled. All corners creased. TRC loss. Surface tears LE: 7/8" from BE, 1/8" from BE. BE: abrasion 12" from LE. Darker patch 10-1/2" from RE, 2-1/4" from BE. Lower RE discolored. Ink stain 1-1/4" from TE, 1-3/4" from RE. TE stained from TRC for 2-1/2" from RE. Spot 10-3/4" from BE, 1/2" from LE. (Box 9)
  - [Unidentified ranch view], ID no. SCW70; Plate Dimensions: 38.5 × 53.5 Mammoth print 17 small losses across TE. RE small tear 5/8" from TE. Abrasion 2-1/4" from TE, 4-1/4" from LE. Loss from 1/2" to 3-1/4" on LE, maximum 1-1/2" deep. Small tears BE 10", 8-1/2", 3-1/2" from LE. Small tear LE 3", 4", 5-1/5" from BE. Cockling CR & TR. No support. (Box 10)
  - [New Almaden Mines], ID no. SCW71; Plate Dimensions: 39 × 52 Matt Dimensions: 54.5 × 67 Mammoth print Smudge 3-3/4" from RE & 1-1/4" from TE. TLC slightly creased. "Restored and remounted 1978 by Jane (?) Onaco (?)" (Box 10)
  - [Casa Grande, Arizona] [long shot], ID no. SCW72; Plate Dimensions: 39.5 × 54 Matt Dimensions: 55.8 × 70.9 Mammoth print No visible damage. All edges cockled. All corners creased. Surface loss all 4 corners. Spot 5-5/8" from BE, 1/2" from RE. Spot 8" from BE, 3/8" from RE. Abrasion 1/2" from TE, 1-5/8" from RE. 1/2" tear TE, 4-7/8" from RE. TE loss 6-3/8" from RE. TE abrasion 14" from RE. (Box 10)
  - [N.C. Carter Ranch, Sierra Madre, Calif., ca. 1876], ID no. SCW73; Plate Dimensions: 39 × 54 Matt Dimensions: 43 × 58 Mammoth print Abrasion 6" from LE, 2-3/8" from TE. All edges cockled. All edges creased. Surface loss BLC & BRC. Loss, surface loss, surface tear TRC. BE tear 4-3/4" from LE. All TE worn. Spot 5-1/8" from BE, 3/16" from LE. Spot 2-3/4" from BE, 1/4" from LE. (Box 10)
  - [Grape Orchard of C.J. Rose Ranch, Sierra Madre, Calif., ca. 1876?], ID no. SCW74; Plate Dimensions: 39 × 54 Matt Dimensions: 44 × 58 Mammoth print Stain from 7" to 9" from BE, 9-3/4" from RE. Abrasions: 9-3/4" from RE, 9-1/2" from BE; 10- 1/8" from RE, 3/8" from TE; 5-7/8" from LE, 4" from TE; 1-1/8" from LE, 7-7/8" from TE. Stain 10-1/8" from RE, 1/2" from TE. V-shaped abrasion 5-1/4" to 6-1/2" from LE, 1-3/4" to 2-1/2" from TE. Abrasions: 3-3/4" from LE, 2-1/2" from TE; 2-1/4" from LE, 2-3/8" from TE. Spots, 2" from LE & 6" from TE, 1-3/4" from LE & 1- 3/4" from TE, 1-1/4" from LE, 2-5/8" from TE. All edges cockled. All corners creased. Loss & surface loss TLC, TRC, BRC. Spots: 1-5/8" from LE, 3/4" from BE; 3-1/2" from LE, 3/4" from BE, 12-1/2" from LE on BE. Stain 4-5/8" from RE, 1/4" from BE. Surface loss on BE from 9-1/4" to 11". Abrasion 1" from BE, 1/8" from RE. Abrasion 3-1/2" from TE, 1/4" from RE. Spots: 5-5/8" from RE & 7/8" from TE; 10" from RE & 1/2" from TE; 4-3/4" from LE & 1/2" from TE;, 3-3/4" from LE & 1/2" from TE. Stain 6-1/2" from RE & 1/4" from TE. (Box 10)
  - [Cajon pass], ID no. SCW75; Plate Dimensions: 37.5 × 47.5 Mammoth print Losses: 4", 7-1/2", 14-3/8", 15-1/8", 16-3/4" from LE. BRC: 2 creases, corner missing. Losses on RE: 3/4", 5", 8-1/8", 11" from BE. LE: losses 3" & 6-1/2" from TE. 1" tear LE 5-1/4" from BE. Small hole 8-1/8" from TE, 1/4" from RE. 3 smudges TE No support. (Box 11)
  - [Cajon pass], Watkins Series no. [1133?]; Plate Dimensions: 10.2 × 15 Copy (not original) (Box 1, Folder 2/5)
  - [Pasadena, ca. 1880, looking north], ID no. SCW76; Plate Dimensions: 37.5 × 53.5 Matt Dimensions: 54.5 × 67 Mammoth print TL & TC: 9 repaired tears. Abrasion 6" from LE & 4-1/4" from TE. Line of stains 10-1/2" from RE extends 4" down from TE. Stain 12" from RE & 1" from TE. TR: 10 stains & 2 repaired tears. RE: abrasion (?) 4-1/4" from BE. Support cockled. (Box 11)
  - Mt. Lola Looking to N.N.W. from below, Watkins Series no. [1253?]; Plate Dimensions: 39 × 54 Matt Dimensions: 49 × 55 Mammoth print Line 5-3/8" from LE, 6-1/4" from TE. Support cockled. LE, TE & RE appear to have been trimmed by a blunt paper cutter. Mount trimmed to very edge of BRC of photograph, fraction of photograph trimmed away with mat. Spot 4-1/8" from LE & 1/2" from BE. (Box 11)
  - [San Xavier Mission, near Tucson, Arizona] Watkins' New Series, 26 New Montgomery Street, San Francisco., [188-?]; Watkins Series no. 1328; Plate Dimensions: 39.5 × 54 Matt Dimensions: 55.5 × 71 Mammoth print Spot 4-7/8" from RE & 1" from TE. All edges cockled. All corners creased. BRC loss. BLC & TRC loss & surface loss. All edges very grubby. BE surface losses 6-1/2" to 7-3/4" from LE; 19-1/2" loss from LE. 1-1/2" abrasion 9-1/4" from LE. Spot 7" from LE & 3/8" from BE. Darker square 1-1/2" to 9-1/2" from RE & 3" to 1-3/4" from BE. Surface loss RE 10-3/8" from BE & 5/8" from RE. TE: crease 4-1/4", 15-1/2", 22-1/4" from RE. (Box 11)
  - [Twin Palms, San Marino], [1878?]; ID no. SCW79; Plate Dimensions: 53 × 37.5 Matt Dimensions: 53 × 37.5 (mounted on cardboard) Mammoth print 9 marks in area 3" from TE & 5-3/4" from RE. TRC creased. TE cut 7-1/2" from RE. TE notch missing 3-1/2" from LE. LE notch 7/16" x 1/4" missing 4" from TE. No support. (Box 11)
- Yosemite
  - [Glacier Point], ID no. SCW100; Matt Dimensions: 16.5 × 10.5 Cabinet card (Box 1, Folder 3/5)
  - [El Capitan and Merced River, Yosemite], ID no. SCW101; Matt Dimensions: 16.5 × 10.5 Cabinet card (Box 1, Folder 3/5)
  - [The Half-Dome from Glacier Point], [ca. 1866]; Watkins Series no. 101; Plate Dimensions: 39 × 51.5 Matt Dimensions: 55.5 × 71 Mammoth print No visible damage. All edges cockled. BLC 1-1/2" missing. BE surface loss 5" from LE. BRC mostly missing. RE tears 7" & 18-3/4" from BE. TRC creased and surface loss. TLC creased and loss. (Box 12)
  - Map of the Yosemite Valley by C. King and J.T. Gardner, 1865; ID no. SCW103; Plate Dimensions: 29 × 47 Matt Dimensions: 47 × 62 Mammoth print Pencil mark in TRC. 1/16" cut (?) 4-1/4" from LE and 3-7/8" from TE. Surface loss RE 1/2" from BE. All edges cockled. Call number, accession number, gift of M.R. Huberty, 10/9/42, on the mount. All corners creased. BRC loss. BLC surface loss. Spot near TRC. 2 spots near TLC. 1" line stain near BLC. Whole surround very grubby. (Box 12)
  - [The Vernal and Nevada Falls from Glacier Point], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 100; Plate Dimensions: 41 × 52 Matt Dimensions: 47 × 62 Mammoth print Spot TE 8-1/2" from RE. Spot 5-5/8" from LE, 3-1/4" from TE. Spot 2-5/8" from LE, 2-3/4" from TE. Spot 1-3/4" from TE, 8-1/2" from LE. Small stain in TLC. All edges cockled. All corners creased. Spot 10" from LE, 1-1/8" from BE. Spot 2-3/4" from RE, 3/4" from BE. Spot 5-1/2" from BE, 2" from RE. Spot 6-1/4" from BE, 1-1/8" from RE. Surface loss TRC. Spot TE 1-5/8" from RE. Spot 7-5/8" from RE, 1-3/8" from TE. Blue smudges in TL. Spot 5" from TE, 1-3/8" from LE. (Box 12)
  - [The Grizzly Giant, Mariposa Grove, 33 ft. diam.], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 110; Plate Dimensions: 52 × 41 Matt Dimensions: 62 × 47 Mammoth print LE: 1/4" faded strip from TE to BE. TE: 1/2" faded strip from LE to RE. All edges cockled. All corners creased. BRC surface loss. TLC loss. Stain 2-1/4" from LE, 2" from BE. Spot 6-7/8" from LE, 1-7/8" from BE. Smudges in BR. Spot 6" from TE, 3/4" from RE. Faint line 5-1/2" from TE, 1/2" from RE. Spot 5-1/4" from LE, 1-1/2" from TE. Spot 5-1/4" from BE, 3/4" from LE. (Box 12)
  - [Section of the Grizzly Giant, Mariposa Grove, 33 ft. diam.], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 113; Plate Dimensions: 52 × 41 Matt Dimensions: 62 × 47 Mammoth print No visible damage. All edges cockled. All corners creased. Spot & smudge, 1-7/8" from LE, 1/2" from BE. Stain 4" to 4-3/8" from BE & from BE to 3/4" from BE. Spot TE 4-1/2" from LE. LE: spot 3/4" from BE. (Box 12)
  - [Outline of the Cathedral Rocks, Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 12; Plate Dimensions: 52 × 41 Matt Dimensions: 62 × 47 Mammoth print General foxing on upper left quarter of photograph. 1/4" faded strip along RE, from TE to BE. All edges cockled. All edges creased. TRC loss. BE stain, 10-3/4" from LE. 1" from BE, 4 spots, 3-1/4", 6-3/4", 13", 16-3/4" from LE. RE: surface loss 13-1/4" from BE. Smudge TR. Series of smudges down left side. (Box 13)
  - [The Bridal Veil from the Coulterville Trail, Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 14; Plate Dimensions: 41 × 52 Matt Dimensions: 47 × 62 Mammoth print TE is grubby. Spot in TL, 2-3/8" from TE, 5" from LE. Stained area 2-1/2" from TE, 2-1/4" from RE. All edges cockled. All corners creased. TLC loss. RE spot, 3" from BE. RE discolored. Surface tear in TRC. LE: 2 spots, 6-7/8" from TE. (Box 13)
  - [Bridal Veil, 900 ft, Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 16; Plate Dimensions: 41 × 52 Matt Dimensions: 47 × 62 Mammoth print Small stain, 3-1/2" from TE, 5-3/4" from LE. Small mark, 5-1/2" from LE, 4-1/2" from TE. BE spot, 6-1/8" from LE. LE: smudge 6-1/4" from BE. (Box 13)
  - [Cathedral Rocks, Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 21; Plate Dimensions: 41 × 52 Matt Dimensions: 47 × 62 Mammoth print Gray patch and zigzag marks near TLC. 1/4" faded strip along BE, from LE to RE. All edges cockled. All corners creased, BLC loss. BE: Small stain 1/2" from BE, 7" from RE. BE: spot, 12" From RE. LE: stain, 9-1/2" from BE. (Box 13)
  - [Cathedral Spires Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 22; Plate Dimensions: 52 × 41 Matt Dimensions: 62 × 47 Mammoth print Slight stain 1/4" to right of left spire. TRC: stain. All edges cockled. All corners creased. Small loss BLC & TRC. Spots near BRC of photograph. Stain 1/2" to right of TRC of photograph. (Box 13)
  - [El Capitan, 3600 ft, Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 26; Plate Dimensions: 41 × 52 Matt Dimensions: 47 × 62 Mammoth print Small hole, 1-3/8" from LE, 2-1/4" from TE. All edges cockled. All corners creased. TLC surface tear. (Box 14)
  - [Half Dome, 5000 ft., Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 62; Plate Dimensions: 41 × 52 Matt Dimensions: 47 × 62 Mammoth print 3/8" faded strip on LE from TE to BE. Stain 1/2" from TE, 11" from RE. All edges cockled. All corners creased. TLC loss. Spot 5-1/8" from RE, 1" from BE. BE spot 2" from RE. Spot BE 1-3/4" from RE. Spot 2-5/8" from TE, 1-3/4" from RE. Spot 1" from TE, 1-1/4" from RE. Spot 1" from TE, 1/4" from RE.. Smudge 7/8" from TE, 11-1/4" from RE. (Box 14)
  - [The North Dome, 3730 ft, Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 63; Plate Dimensions: 41 × 52 Matt Dimensions: 47 × 62 Mammoth print Stain 7-1/2" from LE, 2-5/8" from TE. All edges cockled. All corners creased. Spot 11-3/4" from TE, 1-1/4" from RE. RE spot 6- 3/8" from BE. Spot 11-1/2" from LE, 5/8" from TE. Spot 2" from LE, 1-1/4" from TE. Spot 1-1/2" from LE, 1-1/4" from TE. Stain 11-1/2" from BE, 3/8" from LE. (Box 14)
  - [The Upper House, Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 64; Plate Dimensions: 52 × 41 Matt Dimensions: 62 × 47 Mammoth print No visible damage. All edges cockled. All corners creased. BRC loss. TRC loss & surface loss. Spot 2-5/8" from RE, 7/8" from BE. Spot 12" from TE, 1-1/8" from RE. Spot RE, 5/8" from TE. Spot 13-5/8" from LE, 1- 1/2" from TE. Spot 10-1/4" from LE, 1" from TE. Spot 1-3/8" from BE, 1-3/4" from LE. (Box 14)
  - [Mt. Starr King, Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 69; Plate Dimensions: 52 × 41 Matt Dimensions: 62 × 47 Mammoth print Gray shadowing in TR. Small abrasion 1/2" from LE, 1/2" from TE. All edges cockled. All corners creased. Spot 8-3/4" from RE, 1-1/4" from BE. Smudge 7- 1/2" from TE, 3/4" from RE. Spot 13-1/4" from TE, 1/4" from RE. Spot 9-7/8" from LE, 7/8" from TE. Spot 5-5/8" from LE, 2" from TE. Spot 3" from LE, 2" from TE. Spot LE 6-3/8" from TE. Smudge LE 8" from BE. (Box 14)
  - [Mirror Lake, Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 75; Plate Dimensions: 52 × 41 Matt Dimensions: 62 × 47 Mammoth print Spot 1-1/8" from TE, 3-7/8" from LE. All edges cockled. All corners creased. Spot BE 7-5/8" from LE. Smudge LE 12-1/2" from BE. Spot 1-1/4" from BE, 1/2 from LE. (Box 15)
  - [North Dome, Royal Arches, Washington Column, Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 80; Plate Dimensions: 41 × 52 Matt Dimensions: 47 × 62 Mammoth print Faint black markings near TRC. All edges cockled. All corners creased. Spot 4-5/8" from TE, 1" from RE. Spot 3-1/2" from TE, 1/2" from LE. Smear 6" from BE, 1-1/8" from LE. Spot 3-7/8" from BE, 1-1/4" from LE. (Box 15)
  - [Washington Column, 2082 ft., Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 81; Plate Dimensions: 52 × 41 Matt Dimensions: 62 × 47 Mammoth print Small abrasion 5/8" from TE, 1-1/4" from RE. All edges cockled. All corners creased. Spot 4-3/4" from RE, 7/8" from BE. Spot 5-1/4" from RE, 1/2" from TE. (Box 15)
  - [The North Dome, 3730 ft., Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 85; Plate Dimensions: 52 × 41 Matt Dimensions: 62 × 47 Mammoth print Dark shadowing and black squiggles along TE. All edges cockled. All corners creased. Patch of brown spots 2-3" from LE, 1" from BE. Patch of brown spots 6-1/2" to 7" from LE, 1/4" from BE. Spot 4" from TE, 7/8" from RE. Spot 1" from TE, 1/4" from LE. (Box 15)
  - [The Vernal Fall, 300 ft., Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 88; Plate Dimensions: 52 × 41 Matt Dimensions: 62 × 47 Mammoth print Gray shadowing in sky areas along TE. Black mark, 1-7/8" from TE, 4" from RE. 5/8" faded line down LE, from TE to BE. 1/4" faded line down RE, from TE to BE. All edges cockled. All edges creased. 4 brown spots in BL. RE: stain from 3" to 12-1/4" BE extending to edge of photograph. TE: 1/4" line, 6" from LE. LE: smudge 6" from TE. (Box 15)
  - [Mt. Broderick, Nevada Fall], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 89; Plate Dimensions: 41 × 52 Matt Dimensions: 47 × 62 Mammoth print Smudge TLC. Faded line 3/8" RE from BE to TE. Stain 7-7/8" from RE, 8-1/4" from BE. Stain 7-1/2" from RE, 3" from TE. All edges cockled. All corners creased. Smudges 3-1/4" & 2-1/4" from RE on BE. RE abraded from 5-1/4" to 2-7/8" from TE. Smudge by TLC of photograph. Spot 4-3/4" from BE, 1-3/4" from LE. (Box 16)
  - [Up the Valley from the Foot of the Mariposa Trail], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 9; Plate Dimensions: 41 × 52 Matt Dimensions: 47 × 62 Mammoth print Spot & smudge 6-1/2" from LE and 4" from TE. Spots on TLC. All edges cockled. All corners creased. Surface loss BLC. Loss TLC. Stain near BE 3-12" from LE. Smudge near BRC of photograph. Smudge next to photograph on RE, 4-3/4" from TE. Spots around TLC of photograph. Spots on TE, 8" from LE. (Box 16)
  - [Nevada Fall, 700 ft., Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 90; Plate Dimensions: 41 × 52 Matt Dimensions: 47 × 62 Mammoth print No visible damage. All edges cockled. All corners creased. Spot 9-1/4" from LE, 1" from BE. Spot 1-1/2" from BE, 1/4" from LE. (Box 16)
  - [Nevada Fall, 700 ft., Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 92; Plate Dimensions: 52 × 41 Matt Dimensions: 62 × 47 Mammoth print No visible damage. All edges cockled. All corners creased. BLC loss. TLC surface loss. RE: smudges 10-1/2" from TE. LE: spot 2-1/4" from TE. (Box 16)